<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VS tech corner</title>
    <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on VS tech corner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 18:12:40 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vincentserpoul.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>deploying rust in containers</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/rust-optimized-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 18:12:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/rust-optimized-container/</guid>
      <description>The goal I am pretty familiar with containers and multi stage deployment have been my go to since quite a while now, for my golang codebases.
Now that I have been picking up rust, deploying my first rust service in production did bring me back to my usual habits of containerization.
We&amp;rsquo;ll be trying to optimize for speed of build and container size.
The cargo.toml [...][lib]name = &amp;#34;vs&amp;#34;path = &amp;#34;src/lib.rs&amp;#34;[[bin]]name = &amp;#34;vs&amp;#34;path = &amp;#34;src/bin/vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>golang errors (after 1.13)</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/go-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 12:30:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/go-errors/</guid>
      <description>Since go 1.13, go has gone one step further in terms of error handling. Errors can be wrapped, bubbled up and act upon.
We will here take a step back on error handling in go, from the perspective of a library.
What data could we have in the error? Inspired by a rust talk from Jan Lusby about errors, here are a few things that error could contain:
 The reason of the error Context of the error: struct field, struct surrounding values&amp;hellip; Stack trace: which part of the code triggered this error How to fix the error: suggest a way to fix it  Where are errors displayed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The stable coins</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/stable-coins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 22:50:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/stable-coins/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s crypto world, a few tokens are said stable. that means stable regarding a specific asset, like fiat or even BTC. Here is a compiled list of a few, with information on the way they are backed and audited. sources: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stablecoin
Types of stable coins 💵 fiat based
🪙 crypto curr based
👑 Seigniorage Style Stablecoins (also called algorithmic or synthetic)
List    name symbol backed how? audit     USD Coin USDC 💵 Grant Thornton, LLP 2021   Tether USDT 💵 FSS 2018 2021   Binance dollar BUSD 💵 Withum 2021   Gemini dollar GUSD 💵 bpmca 2021   Maker DAO dai DAI 🪙 300% smart contracts   True USD TUSD 💵 armanino 2021   StableUnit SU 🪙 smart contracts   Paxos standard PAX 💵 Withum 2021   Terra UST 👑 smart contracts   Ampleforth AMPL 👑 smart contracts   Augmint A-EUR 👑 smart contracts   Frax FRAX 🪙 👑 smart contracts   sUSD sUSD 🪙 👑 smart contracts   mStable mUSD 🪙 👑 smart contracts   Fei FEI 🪙 👑 smart contracts    Stability and risk The criterias to evaluate the different platforms and protocols would be among the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>golang 1.16 new feature: embed</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/go-embed-1.16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 18:39:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/go-embed-1.16/</guid>
      <description>What is it about In previous versions of go, you needed to reach out for an external package in order to embed static content inside your binary.
My go to one was shurcool/vfsgen, but there were many others worth using.
Go 1.16 brings a new package, &amp;ldquo;embed&amp;rdquo;, which allows to do that with just the standard library.
How to do that The best part of this, it&amp;rsquo;s extremely simple, just see for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wasm Prez</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/wasm-intro-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 13:38:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/wasm-intro-talk/</guid>
      <description>I presented at voxxed days last week.
Here is the talk I gave, video coming when it&amp;rsquo;s published.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>testing mozilla iot gateway</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/mozilla-iot-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:23:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/mozilla-iot-gateway/</guid>
      <description>Mozilla iot gateway Here is what I am going to setup. I am obviously not going to rewrite one more time the tutorial and docs from mozilla. I will simply describe the specific setup I used, and the little things I setup to make it work.
Prerequisites  Raspberry pi 3b Zigbee dongle, zwave dongle list of compatible hardware - I used Digi XStick (ZB mesh version) and Aeotec Z-Stick (Gen5) Zigbee Smart bulb (i used a philips hue), zigbee motion detector (I used philips motion sensor)  Linux I used my favorite lean alpine linux, with the setup as I explained in this post minus the complexity brought up by the rpi0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cross compiling rust from linux to rpi0/alpine</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/alpine-rpi0-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 19:02:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/alpine-rpi0-rust/</guid>
      <description>If you read my previous posts, you should now have a raspberry-pi running alpine and docker.
Resources are pretty limited on rpi0, so we are going to deploy programs using rust. Note: golang could have fit in there as well (and ofc all C and close to machine languages).
Compiling from NOT a rpi0 Obviously, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to compile from a raspberry pi zero, unless you have all the time in the world and love waiting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>installing docker on alpine linux</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/alpine-linux-rpi0-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 11:07:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/alpine-linux-rpi0-docker/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  One raspberry pi zero W One sd card  Enable all cgroups On you local linux, mount the partition containing alpine files.
In the cmdline.txt, add the following:
echo -ne &amp;#34; cgroup_enable=memory cgroup_enable=cpuset swapaccount=1&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /run/media/youruser/xxx/cmdline.txt Docker needs all cgroups enabled, so this will do the trick
On you rpi0 As simple as:
sudo apk add docker sudo rc-update add docker boot sudo rc-service docker start To make sure your docker env doesn&amp;rsquo;t go in memory (512MB RAM won&amp;rsquo;t bring you far&amp;hellip;), set it on mmcblk0p3 by editing /etc/docker/daemon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>installing alpine linux on rpi0</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/alpine-linux-rpi0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 21:22:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/alpine-linux-rpi0/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  One raspberry pi zero W One sd card  Download Alpine linux We&amp;rsquo;ll use the almost latest version: 3.9.2 (3.9.3 would not work for some reason) The one to use for RPI is the raspberry pi (surprising :P) armhf.
On your local computer (assuming you re using linux) Mount the sdcard (should be automated, if not, you probably know how to do that and you probably don&amp;rsquo;t need that tutorial)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>golang binaries</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/golang-binary-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 09:22:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/golang-binary-everything/</guid>
      <description>Embedding anything in a golang binary What is it about? One good thing about golang is that you compile everything to a binary. So easy to deploy, so easy to manage, so small.
But what happens when you need to embed files in there? Migration files, static files, whatever you can think of?
Well, you can simply deploy it in a container, add this files, you are going to say, and you are probably right, that&amp;rsquo;s imho, the cleanest solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a taste of wasm</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/playwithwasm-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 23:22:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/playwithwasm-golang/</guid>
      <description>Here it is, go 1.11 is out, and with it a new compilation target, Web Assembly!
Let&amp;rsquo;s try it out!
The test As dumb as it sounds, I needed a simple usecase to test this out. I decided to settle for the dumbest possible thing: a for loop incrementing a variable for 100000000 times.
The git repo Here it is
I uploaded it as well on surge for you to see without the hassle</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using GKE with multiple accounts and clusters</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/gke-multi-accounts-clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 11:37:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/gke-multi-accounts-clusters/</guid>
      <description>Google cloud configs Download and install gcloud Simply follow this link
Listing existing configurations gcloud config configurations list NAME IS_ACTIVE ACCOUNT PROJECT DEFAULT_ZONE DEFAULT_REGION This should give you only one line, with a default account.
Creating a configuration gcloud config configurations create testconf This will guide you through the configuration of a new configuration. It allows you to set one config per account, project, cluster&amp;hellip;
Activating a configuration gcloud config configurations activate testconf As simple as this to change your account/config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bluetooth activation at startup on arch linux</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/archlinux-bluetooth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 16:22:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/archlinux-bluetooth/</guid>
      <description>Why? You might not have reach that point yet but bluez has been deprecating hciconfig and other tools. In bluez 5.44, it&amp;rsquo;s not there anymore.
What is the problem? All hciconfig udev rules to activate bluetooth at startup won&amp;rsquo;t work anymore. Most forum posts solving bluetooth issues are now outdated. Once I updated to bluez 5.44, my service leveraging hciconfig to activate bluetooth at startup didn&amp;rsquo;t work anymore!
What is the solution?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang and Oracle</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/golang-playwithsql-oracle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 00:44:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/golang-playwithsql-oracle/</guid>
      <description>Which library To this day, the most up to date library seems to be rana/ora
How to install (linux &amp;amp; macosx) Download Oracle Instant Client for linux x64: both packages Basic and SDK Unzip each of them in the same folder /opt/oracle
mkdir -p /opt/oracle cd /opt/oracle unzip ~/Downloads/instantclient-basiclite-linux.x64-12.2.0.1.0.zip unzip ~/Downloads/instantclient-sdk-linux.x64-12.2.0.1.0.zip cd /opt/oracle/instantclient_12_1 Add the necessary env variables and paths:
# Oracle export LD_LIBRARY_PATH=/opt/oracle/instantclient_12_2:$LD_LIBRARY_PATH export PKG_CONFIG_PATH=/opt/oracle export ORACLE_HOME=$LD_LIBRARY_PATH copy from the go package .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethereum react dapps</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-react-dapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 13:34:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-react-dapps/</guid>
      <description>I finished my first dapp with (react-boilerplate)[https://github.com/mxstbr/] this week and here are the few things I learnt. I won&amp;rsquo;t get into the redux, redux-saga details, I let you play with the amazing boilerplate.
Interacting with constant functions Let&amp;rsquo;s use the typical balanceOf function of the EIP20 contracts:
function balanceOf(address _owner) constant returns (uint256 balance) { return balances[_owner]; } Here are the sagas (redux-sagas) I used to interact:
import { take, call, put, cancel, select, fork } from &amp;#39;redux-saga/effects&amp;#39;; import { BALANCE_OF_GET, } from &amp;#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethereum contracts and Golang</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/binding-ethereum-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 12:54:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/binding-ethereum-golang/</guid>
      <description>The contract contract Trigger { function () { throw; } address owner; function Trigger() { owner = msg.sender; } event TriggerEvt(address _sender, uint _trigger); function trigger(uint _trigger) { TriggerEvt(msg.sender, _trigger); } function getOwner() constant returns (address) { return owner; } } This is a very simple contract that we will take as an example.
Getting the right tools for binding A good starting point is this wiki.
You will need to follow the install procedure of go-ethereum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of UBER lessons on scaling microservices</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/on-microservices-and-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 12:06:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/on-microservices-and-scaling/</guid>
      <description>I just watched that amazing videos from Matt Ranney
Here are my takeaways and opinionated summary:
 Use RPC for service to service communications: gRPC seems to be a good way of tackling it Use many repositories Profiling should be unified: flamegraphs seem to be a good solution (Go profiling is great too) Premature optimization is bad but performance monitoring is crucial! Trace requests, keep context within all logs Log a lot, but only on a portion of your production architecture as logging can have a big cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain week in Shanghai!</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-solidity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 13:44:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-solidity/</guid>
      <description>I participated to the devcon2 and blockchain summit last week. Here is my summary!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethereum first dapp - part 3</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-first-dapp-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 12:00:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-first-dapp-part-3/</guid>
      <description>setting up a light wallet In order to have a setup close to what the DAPP would be, we will use (metamask) [http://www.metamask.io] as a light wallet (there are other choices).
Metamask allows you to connect to a custom node.
We will then connect to our node, http://localhost:9012 If everthing is fine, metamasks should indicate it&amp;rsquo;s connected.
Then, we can import the metamask account to our local node by simply specifying the datadir we have setup the node data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethereum first dapp - part 2</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-first-dapp-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 15:00:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-first-dapp-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Frontend Prepare your folder for your dapp I will be using https://github.com/mxstbr/react-boilerplate as it&amp;rsquo;s quite nice and I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with React for a bit now.
I will not go into the details of setting this up, it&amp;rsquo;s a totally different topic. If you are not familiar with it, it&amp;rsquo;s probably a waste of time for you to read.
Example web3 component with React This boilerplate uses immutable, redux and redux-sagas in order to deal with data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethereum first dapp - part 1</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-first-dapp-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 15:00:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-first-dapp-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Contracts Prepare your folder for your dapp mkdir dapp inside this folder, we&amp;rsquo;ll create one folder for truffle, one for geth.
cd dapp mkdir truffle geth inside the geth folder, simply put the customGenesis block you can find in the ethereum-dev-environment blog post.
We are going to use two Ethereum clients, one for tests and devs, testrpc and one for a more real interaction, geth.
Let&amp;rsquo;s install truffle and testrpc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interacting with an Ethereum smart contract</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-interacting-with-contracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 20:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-interacting-with-contracts/</guid>
      <description>Check the address of the current deployed contract Remember when you mined your contract, it told your its address. Now, reuse it!
eth.getCode(&amp;quot;0x5f3425ccedeae0eb36521c4cf93ec6544dbad9bd&amp;quot;) Test the contract with a simple interaction get the latest web3-light.min.js js from https://github.com/ethereum/web3.js/releases and simply copy the dist/web3-light.min.js into the same folder as the following HTML file.
then, use this html to interact with your contract on the local node:
&amp;lt;!doctype&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script type=&amp;#34;text/javascript&amp;#34; src=&amp;#34;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/bignumber.js/2.4.0/bignumber.min.js&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script type=&amp;#34;text/javascript&amp;#34; src=&amp;#34;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethereum first smart contract</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-first-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 13:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-first-contract/</guid>
      <description>Launch your geth (or testrpc) private instance ./geth \  --identity &amp;#34;gethTest&amp;#34; \  --rpc --rpcport &amp;#34;9012&amp;#34; \  --rpccorsdomain &amp;#34;YOUR_TEST_DOMAIN_APP_RUN_FROM&amp;#34; \  --datadir &amp;#34;./testChain&amp;#34; \  --port &amp;#34;30303&amp;#34; \  --nodiscover \  --rpcapi &amp;#34;db,eth,net,web3&amp;#34; \  --networkid 1999 \  --dev console Within the console, compile your contract check this tutorial: https://www.ethereum.org/greeter
I had an issue when I followed the contract tutorial, my contract would not be mined after I was trying to deploy it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethereum dev environment</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-dev-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 08:27:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/ethereum-dev-environment/</guid>
      <description>Part 1 - Setup your ethereum node There are many ways you can setup a node to dev an Ethereum dapp. You can use the live network: not advisable obviously for cost and speed reasons. You can use the test network: not advisable for speed reasons. You can use a testchain set up with Geth: easy but a bit tedious as you need to mine. You can the ethereum testrpc: easiest!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Singapore Birthday Event</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/kubernetes-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 22:27:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/kubernetes-talk/</guid>
      <description>On the 28th, I was invited to talk at Google Singapore for the Kubernetes birthday http://www.meetup.com/fr-FR/GCPUGSG/events/232659329/?eventId=232659329
I spoke about my experience with Kubernetes in production for one of my side projects.
As I like to experiment stuff, I decide to drop power point and use React Spectacle library for my presentation!
here is the result: https://kuberneprez.surge.sh
here is the source code: https://github.com/vincentserpoul/prez-kubernetes
The framework can be found here: http://stack.formidable.com/spectacle/#/?_k=cyx05u
I will do it again!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>learning react</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/learning-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 12:22:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/learning-react/</guid>
      <description>React Nothing beats the facebook React page:
https://facebook.github.io/react/docs/getting-started.html
Redux Nothing beats the redux tutorial:
http://redux.js.org/
And also available on egghead, by Dan Abramov himself:
https://egghead.io/series/getting-started-with-redux
A list of tutorials:
https://github.com/happypoulp/redux-tutorial
A great detailed introduction to your SPA setup http://blog.joanboixados.com/building-a-boilerplate-for-a-koa-redux-react-application-including-webpack-mocha-and-sass/
An advanced SPA (still under construction) https://www.gitbook.com/book/tonyhb/redux-without-profanity/details</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>react setup with essential tools</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/react-dev-env-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 20:48:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/react-dev-env-setup/</guid>
      <description>Working with ES6-7 In order to work with ECMAScript 2015 and even with future implementations of ES, you can use Babel.
Babel is a transpiler, it will convert your ES6-7 to plain ES5 javascript that most browsers (&amp;gt;ie9 most probably) will understand.
To install babel
npm install -g babel Then within your javascript project, you can create a .babelrc file with the following content:
{ &amp;#34;presets&amp;#34;: [&amp;#34;es2015&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;stage-0&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;react&amp;#34;] } React and its surrounding libraries After starting using React, I realized it was vey good and was surrounded with libraries which makes it even better: redux, immutable, react-router&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>javascript dev environment setup</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/javascript-dev-env-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 20:48:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/javascript-dev-env-setup/</guid>
      <description>NodeJS Go to the nodejs website and install nodejs latest stable version:
https://nodejs.org/en/download/stable/
NPM Go to the npm website and follow the instructions
https://docs.npmjs.com/getting-started/installing-node
Install nodejs essential packages npm install -g eslint webpack webpack-dev-server babel-eslint serve
Install sublime-text essential plugins With the help of the package manager, in sublime-text, install the following packages: babel, Sublime-Linter-Contrib-eslint, React ES6 snippets
Make sure your linter is working In sublime text, open the console (view &amp;gt; show console) and check if there is any error message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>golang dev environment setup</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/golang-dev-env-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 20:48:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/golang-dev-env-setup/</guid>
      <description>Golang environment install golang
http://www.wolfe.id.au/2015/03/05/using-sublime-text-for-go-development/
Within sublimetext, from the package manager, install gosublime, install gooracle.
install go/tools:
go get -u golang.org/x/tools/cmd/goimports go get -u golang.org/x/tools/cmd/vet go get -u golang.org/x/tools/cmd/oracle go get -u golang.org/x/tools/cmd/godoc install gometalinter (https://github.com/alecthomas/gometalinter)
install interfacer (https://github.com/mvdan/interfacer/)
install gosimple (https://github.com/dominikh/go-simple)
install gocov (https://github.com/axw/gocov)
Here is the package settings I use for gosublime:
{ // you may set specific environment variables here // e.g &amp;#34;env&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;PATH&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;$HOME/go/bin:$PATH&amp;#34; } // in values, $PATH and ${PATH} are replaced with // the corresponding environment(PATH) variable, if it exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sublime text setup with essential tools</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/sublimetext-dev-env-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 20:48:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/sublimetext-dev-env-setup/</guid>
      <description>Download and install the latest Sublime text Go to the sublime text website and download Sublime text 3 for your OS.
https://www.sublimetext.com/3
Download and install the sublime text package manager Go the package control website, download and install it on your sublime text (follow the instructions on the website).
https://packagecontrol.io/installation
Download and install sublime linter Go to the sublime linter website, download and install it on your sublime text.
http://www.sublimelinter.com/en/latest/installation.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIT basic usage</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/git-basic-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 08:27:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/post/git-basic-usage/</guid>
      <description>Git basic commands When you have a new repo git clone git@github.com:vincentserpoul/rbac.git https or git? the git protocal provides better security and easiness if you are using a correct key.
If you use the git protocol, you can easily associate your private key in the ~/.ssh/config file with the following:
Host github Hostname github.com User vincentserpoul IdentityFile ~/.ssh/myprivatekey IdentitiesOnly yes When you have a new modification ready for commit git status You will get an overview of what&amp;rsquo;s new If there is any new files (Untracked files), you will first need to add them:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 14:46:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vincentserpoul.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Try out for Hugo!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
